Next thing we're going to talk about is the club face and specifically the grooves on the club face.
You know you see a lot of those professional golfers out there on Sunday afternoon hitting these wedge shots, having them check up, having them spin, the reason why they're creating that spin on that golf ball I should say is because of the grooves in their wedges.
It's really important when your out on the golf course to keep these grooves clean and if you have a bunch of mud on that club face it's not going to spin.
A perfect example of this is with your driver.
If you take a look at the driver you'll notice there are no grooves on the club face of the driver.
This reason being is you want to minimize the spin on the golf ball.
Now take a look at your wedge these grooves are going to be deeper and they're going to be a little bit wider and this is really important when controlling the spin on the golf ball.
The closer you get to the green you want to be able to control the golf ball and stopping when you want it to stop.
Same thing applies with the irons.
If you take a look at the face club of an iron same thing, you want to keep those clean.
This is just really important when it comes to the control of your golf ball.
That can also go into the types of golf balls which we can go into later and what the right golf ball is for you and what you should look at when you go into your golf shop.